<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>untitledthoughts on Ram Goli</title>
    <link>https://ramgo.li/tags/untitledthoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in untitledthoughts on Ram Goli</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 22:20:40 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ramgo.li/tags/untitledthoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled Thoughts: On Giving Up</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/on-giving-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 22:20:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/on-giving-up/</guid>
      <description>So many articles out there preach &amp;ldquo;proven methods to never give up.&amp;rdquo; We live in such a fast-paced society where execution and forward progress is worshipped. Quitting on a challenge, task, or idea can make us feel weak, and is often frowned upon. It feels like we aren&amp;rsquo;t strong enough to finish what we set out to accomplish, or like we don&amp;rsquo;t have the mental resolve to persevere. Giving up practicing the trumpet after starting college always nagged at the back of my mind like a lonely child who tugs at the bottom of his father&amp;rsquo;s coat, innocently pleading for more attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled Thoughts: Free Will</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/free-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 22:06:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/free-will/</guid>
      <description>Free will doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist. The idea that humans have control over their thoughts, and thus over their actions, can not be true. We are an amalgamation of chemical and biological processes, which obey the laws of physics, rather than our own will. Given any set of inputs, our brains will always act in the same manner, every time. It&amp;rsquo;s like plugging in values into some convoluted quadratic formula. If you give the equation the same inputs, it will always output the same value.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>