<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Ram Goli</title>
		<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Ram Goli</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 22:21:02 -0700</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://ramgo.li/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>Learning To Ask</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/just-ask/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 22:21:02 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/just-ask/</guid>
			<description>Solving your own problems is next to impossible when you have no idea where to begin. This glaring issue strikes me so often at work, and even more so in my personal life. I am faced with some challenging hurdle to jump over, but I have no context to draw help from.
I think the biggest blocker in these situations is my hesitancy to turn to someone else for help. There was a time when I was taking CS131 and was stuck on the third or fourth homework assignment for what felt like days.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Solving your own problems is next to impossible when you have no idea where to begin.
This glaring issue strikes me so often at work, and even more so in my personal life.
I am faced with some challenging hurdle to jump over, but I have no context to
draw help from.<br />
<br />
I think the biggest blocker in these situations is my hesitancy to turn to someone
else for help. There was a time when I was taking CS131 and was stuck on the third or fourth
homework assignment for what felt like days. When talking to a friend about my dilemma, she
offered to help me come up with a working solution. I felt disappointed in myself that I was
handing in a homework assignment that I didn&rsquo;t fully understand. I would hole myself up alone in
the library while my friends all gathered together, sharing snacks and tips. I needed to do things
myself, my own way. I realized that I equated asking for help with an admission of weakness in myself. I felt very
vulnerable thinking about it that way.<br />
<br />
I had a conversation with my manager early in the summer on the topic of coming up with
solutions to one&rsquo;s problems that started to change my outlook on this feeling.
He shared with me some insight on the idea of <em>social bandwidth</em>.
There are plenty of great reasons to ask someone for help: people are good at explaining things in their domain of expertise.
However, their capability to do so is limited. This limit defines their social bandwidth, and once they have exhausted it,
each subsequent question they are asked receives a degraded response. People are not receptive
to loads of questions that are poorly thought out. This means that
meaningful questions, when asked with as much prior understanding as possible, result in high quality
answers. Do your due diligence in finding solutions on your own, and when you are faced with
the hurdle you can no longer jump over, ask.<br />
<br />
I&rsquo;m realizing now the power of asking the right amount
of the right questions. Thinking about the social bandwidth of those around me empowers me
to try and find answers to my own questions, and often I suceed even before needing to reach
out to someone else. I&rsquo;ve started to shift my perception of <em>asking</em> from one of admitting
weakness to one of persevering. <em>I&rsquo;ve done all I can to solve
this question, and I am too determined now to let the answer elude me any longer. There are
people out there who can help me through this.</em></p>

<p>Asking for help is still hard for me, but I&rsquo;m getting better. I know that I&rsquo;m surrounded
wherever I go by empathetic and loving individuals. I would not hesitate to help them if needed,
and I know they would do the same for me.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Living Content</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/living-content/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 21:17:15 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/living-content/</guid>
			<description>I just came back from a camping trip with friends with several fresh thoughts ready to brew.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved being entrenched in the wilderness, ever since I went on my first mountain biking trip through the careening hill of Mt. Tam during the sixth grade. I even wrote my UC college essay on that experience, and it somehow landed me a spot in UCLA. Crazy.
Anyways, being lost in the trees has always been the state of being that I gravitate to most.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just came back from a camping trip with friends with several fresh thoughts
ready to brew.<br />
<br />
I&rsquo;ve always loved being entrenched in the wilderness, ever since I went on my
first mountain biking trip through the careening hill of Mt. Tam during the sixth
grade. I even wrote my UC college essay on that experience, and it somehow landed
me a spot in UCLA. Crazy.</p>

<p>Anyways, being lost in the trees has always been the state of being that I gravitate to
most. I&rsquo;ve always thought about one day moving myself out somewhere near the wilderness.
I could work a simple job, live on a large plot of land, raise my own sheep and chicken.
I would probably be really happy too. It doesn&rsquo;t take much to make a human happy. We only
require so much basic sustenance.<br />
<br />
Would I be really satisfied though? I know what I am capable of, and the thought of throwing
away that potential is daunting. I could work as a successful software engineer
in a big city, or start my own company and build something amazing on my own.
How much am I willing to sacrifice?</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Being a Better Child</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/being-a-better-child/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 23:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/being-a-better-child/</guid>
			<description>I suspect that I haven&amp;rsquo;t been a very good child as of late. I often forget to text my mother back. I don&amp;rsquo;t spend as much time with my parents when I&amp;rsquo;m back home as I should. I find myself subconsciously avoiding conversation with them, rather than investing in it. These facts have led me to come up with a list of demands for myself/habits to form. Here goes.
 I will text my mother once every day I will call my parents (at least) every other day Before going back to school, I will spend (at least) one entire day solely in their company I will verbally tell them how important they are to me and my success  It&amp;rsquo;s time to stop feeling guilty for being a distant son.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I suspect that I haven&rsquo;t been a very good child as of late. I often forget to text my mother back.
I don&rsquo;t spend as much time with my parents when I&rsquo;m back home as I should. I find myself subconsciously
avoiding conversation with them, rather than investing in it. These facts have led me to come up with a list
of demands for myself/habits to form. Here goes.</p>

<ul>
<li>I will text my mother once every day</li>
<li>I will call my parents (at least) every other day</li>
<li>Before going back to school, I will spend (at least) one entire day solely in their company</li>
<li>I will verbally tell them how important they are to me and my success</li>
</ul>

<p>It&rsquo;s time to stop feeling guilty for being a distant son.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Internal Debates</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/internal-debates/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 23:43:20 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/internal-debates/</guid>
			<description>I spend way too much time in my own head.
I am often the moderator of a debate between two bitter enemies clashing head to head, which takes place after nearly every social interaction I have with people. Voice #1 in my head will say &amp;ldquo;Ram, you should&amp;rsquo;ve said this just a minute ago,&amp;rdquo; while Voice #2 will immediately interject with a &amp;ldquo;No Ram, you should&amp;rsquo;ve said that instead.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<figure>
    <img src="/img/debate/trapped.jpeg"/> 
</figure>


<p>I spend way too much time in my own head.<br />
<br />
I am often the moderator of a debate between two
bitter enemies clashing head to head, which takes place after nearly
every social interaction I have with people. Voice #1 in my head will say &ldquo;Ram, you should&rsquo;ve
said <em>this</em> just a minute ago,&rdquo; while Voice #2 will immediately interject with a &ldquo;No Ram, you
should&rsquo;ve said <em>that</em> instead.&rdquo; I&rsquo;ll replay the interaction in my head over and over,
imagining every possible way the conversation could have been steered towards something more
interesting or productive.<br />
<br />
I know this can&rsquo;t be a healthy habit. Soon enough, I&rsquo;m going to start having these internal
debates mid-conversation with people, and I will freeze. I will be unable to pick which voice in my head I want
to give the microphone too. Funny enough however, the more time I spend writing these blog
posts, the more time I spend locked in my own head, replaying how exactly each sentence sounds,
debating whether to keep it or reword. Blogging is both unleashing my voice for
the world to hear, and trapping me with my own unrestrained thoughts. Ah, the cruel
irony.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Motivation</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/motivation/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 23:32:42 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/motivation/</guid>
			<description>Finding motivation to accomplish something can be a difficult challenge, especially when you need to also motivate those around you. Talking about how difficult the job can be if not everyone is doing their part can dampen spirits, and relying on enthusiasm and excitement in your speech is not always sustainable.
I think the best way to bring out motivation in others is create alignment. If you start with a high level mission, a &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re going to Mars&amp;rdquo; type moonshot, its easy to break it down into several sub-objectives in support of that high level mission, and continue to break them down into actionable accomplishments.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Finding motivation to accomplish something can be a difficult challenge, especially
when you need to also motivate those around you. Talking about how difficult
the job can be if not everyone is doing their part can dampen spirits, and relying on
enthusiasm and excitement in your speech is not always sustainable.<br />
<br />
I think the best way to bring out motivation in others is create alignment.
If you start with a high
level mission, a &ldquo;We&rsquo;re going to Mars&rdquo; type moonshot, its easy to break it down
into several sub-objectives in support of that high level mission, and continue
to break them down into actionable accomplishments. People will usually latch onto this chain of missions somewhere
along the line and find one they resonate with. When everyone is latched on, and can see how
their efforts will work their way up the chain in service of the objective, motivation runs high.<br />
<br />
I&rsquo;ve been thinking about this strategy in the context of running a company or a campus club,
but I&rsquo;d like to figure out how I can use this technique to motivate myself everyday. How
do I get myself to go on that run, or prep for that interview coming up, or speak to that peron I see often
but feel timid around. What is that thing that I need to align myself towards? Do I care
about doing the most good for the world? Do I prioritize making enough money to support myself
and my future family? Can I somehow align both of these into a higher mission? How the hell
do I know when I&rsquo;ve found the right alignment chain, and how much time do I even have ??</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Untitled Thoughts: Free Will</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/free-will/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 22:06:04 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/free-will/</guid>
			<description>Free will doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist. The idea that humans have control over their thoughts, and thus over their actions, can not be true. We are an amalgamation of chemical and biological processes, which obey the laws of physics, rather than our own will. Given any set of inputs, our brains will always act in the same manner, every time. It&amp;rsquo;s like plugging in values into some convoluted quadratic formula. If you give the equation the same inputs, it will always output the same value.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Free will doesn&rsquo;t exist. The idea that humans have control over their thoughts, and thus over their actions,
can not be true. We are an amalgamation of chemical and biological processes, which obey the laws of physics, rather
than our own will. Given any set of inputs, our brains will always act in the same manner, every time. It&rsquo;s like plugging
in values into some convoluted quadratic formula. If you give the equation the same inputs, it will always
output the same value. Who is to say our brains act any differently? And if this really is the case, if our brains are truly
deterministic, we have no control over them.<br />
<br />
Moral of the story: don&rsquo;t get too worked up over life. It&rsquo;s happening the way it&rsquo;s meant to be, and there is no other
way.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Confirmation Bias</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/confirmation-bias/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 15:47:27 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/confirmation-bias/</guid>
			<description>We largely tune into the same news channels, follow the same twitter feeds, subscribe to the same youtube channels that feed into our already fine-tuned perception of the outside world, of the &amp;ldquo;other side.&amp;rdquo; We hang out with those who espouse the same beliefs we do, and are quick to dismiss the opinions coming from the opposite end of the spectrum.
No individual is at fault for demonstrating such commonplace behavior.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We largely tune into the same news channels, follow the same twitter feeds, subscribe to the same youtube channels
that feed into our already fine-tuned perception of the outside world, of the &ldquo;other side.&rdquo; We hang out with
those who espouse the same beliefs we do, and are quick to dismiss the opinions coming from the opposite end of the
spectrum.<br />
<br />
No individual is at fault for demonstrating such commonplace behavior.
Our bodies are always fighting to remain in harmony, and words from politicians that we perceive as vile or unethical
introduce unwanted entropy into our minds.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>When opposing facts challenge your identity, your brain perceives the psychological threat
and protects you as if it was an actual physical threat. — Psychology Today</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This is <em>confirmation bias</em> at work. It&rsquo;s not difficult to succumb to it either. If we see someone on Twitter or Facebook
who shares the same views as us, we hit the follow button or send them a friend request. Soon, our feeds are populated
with more of the same ideas that we already held to be true. If we encounter someone in these social media networks
who says things that make us uncomfortable, we block or mute them, throwing those mutinous crew members off the ship and
continuing to sail onwards along the same route.<br />
I&rsquo;ve encountered this firsthand - my own friends will refuse to engage in conversation over dissenting views, even when
I acknowledge that I share the same ones they do. I&rsquo;ve been called <em>thick-skinned</em>, <em>frustrating</em>, <em>impossible</em> all for
surfacing ideas that I don&rsquo;t even believe in, but believe important to talk about.<br />
<br />
Confirmation bias is a dangerous trap that we all, myself included, often fall prey to. I mean, <em>know thine enemy</em>,
or something like that, right? How are we supposed to defeat the enemy if we can&rsquo;t even listen to them, empathize with
their arguments, and then construct the right points to take them down? Sometimes, (who knows), they may know something
that we don&rsquo;t.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>The Universal Adapter</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/the-universal-adapter/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 23:47:45 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/the-universal-adapter/</guid>
			<description>The Universal Adapter, in my own words, possesses the unique trait of hyper-compatibility. Anyone can approach the Univeral Adapter, plug into them, and instantly be exposed to a source of warmth and friendship. A Universal Adapter is an idealized social construct - a human being capable of befriending anyone.
Does the Universal Adapter exist?
And if so, how is it possible? How can someone truly be friends with anyone?
I&amp;rsquo;ve recently stumbled across the key to universal compatibility, thanks to the prior work of my new friend AB.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <em>Universal Adapter</em>, in my own words, possesses the unique trait of hyper-compatibility.
Anyone can approach the <em>Univeral Adapter</em>, plug into them, and instantly be exposed to a source
of warmth and friendship. A <em>Universal Adapter</em> is an idealized social construct - a human being capable of befriending <em>anyone</em>.<br />
<br />
Does the Universal Adapter exist?</p>

<p>And if so, how is it possible? How can someone truly be friends with anyone?<br />
<br />
I&rsquo;ve recently stumbled across the key to universal compatibility, thanks to the prior work of my new friend AB.
The secret is time. The longer you spend in someone&rsquo;s presence, the more refined your ability is to see what makes them laugh,
what exasperates them, what draws their ire and what makes them feel light and dreamy. I can be friends with
anyone, so long as I put conscious effort in spending more time with them. That means inviting them to spend
their lunch with you, or asking them about their next spot to visit on a Taco Tuesay (and maybe even
butting your way into their plans). No matter your assumptions of a person&rsquo;s pre-existing reservations
or judgements, you can find a form-fitting spot for yourself in their life - if you just be present.
You are a univeral adapter.</p>

<hr />

<p><em>Why am I writing this? Not too long ago, I used to believe that there were innate qualities about me that
would bar myself from befriending certain types of people. Some peole are just too cool for me,
and would be uninterested in associating with me. It was an assumption that perhaps stemmed
from my recent lack of self-esteem. It is more or less bullshit now. Everyday, I observe firsthand
the power that simply being present in someone&rsquo;s life can have. If I cast aside whatever
inhibitions I have regarding someone, and allow myself to spend time with them, I can befriend
anyone. I&rsquo;m writing this to remind myself
that I don&rsquo;t have to discredit my ability to be a universal adapter.</em></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Cognitive Dissonance</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/cognitive-dissonance/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 23:12:33 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/cognitive-dissonance/</guid>
			<description>The feeling of discomfort when your beliefs run counter to your behaviors.
 It&amp;rsquo;s that itch that you can&amp;rsquo;t seem to scratch deep within the back of your mind. What do you do to get rid of it? You only have two options right? You either change your beliefs, or you change your behaviors.
But what if you can&amp;rsquo;t just change either? You&amp;rsquo;ve become too comfortable with your behavior to justify doing anything else, and you&amp;rsquo;re too stubborn to let go of your beliefs so easily.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>The feeling of discomfort when your beliefs run counter to your behaviors.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It&rsquo;s that itch that you can&rsquo;t seem to scratch deep within the back of your mind. What do you
do to get rid of it? You only have two options right? You either change your beliefs,
or you change your behaviors.<br />
<br />
But what if you can&rsquo;t just change either? You&rsquo;ve become too comfortable with your behavior to
justify doing anything else, and you&rsquo;re too stubborn to let go of your beliefs so easily. Now your cognitive
dissonance has just intensified, because you realize that something needs to change, but you aren&rsquo;t strong
enough to do anything about it. It&rsquo;s quite a shitty situation.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>There Is No Right Answer</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/there-is-no-right-answer/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 22:55:53 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/there-is-no-right-answer/</guid>
			<description>The questions that bother me the most are the ones that I can never come up with an answer to. They leave behind a queasy aftertaste that I just can&amp;rsquo;t get rid of. I love being proven wrong in an argument, because the defeat will add something new to my repertoire of reasoning. But when we reach a stalemate, it feels queasy, and unsatisfactory. We made it so far, right to the edge of the cliff overlooking the eager blue waters below, but we won&amp;rsquo;t make the jump.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The questions that bother me the most are the ones that I can never come up with an answer to.
They leave behind a queasy aftertaste that I just can&rsquo;t get rid of. I love being proven wrong
in an argument, because the defeat will add something new to my repertoire of reasoning.
But when we reach a stalemate, it feels queasy, and unsatisfactory. We made it so far, right to the edge of the cliff
overlooking the eager blue waters below, but we won&rsquo;t make the jump.<br />
<br />
Here is a question for you to ponder: is PDA (public display of affection) a good or bad thing? I myself am against PDA. I always
felt that it creates exclusion between a group of people or friends all hanging out together, separating
two people from the rest. I would much rather have everyone hang out as one unit. I tried arguing
this point with a friend, who firmly held her ground in support of the opposite answer. PDA can
reaffirm the comfort and fondness you have with your partner. If you are surrounded by your
friends, they are probably used to the affection between the two of you, and so the PDA you share
is not disconcerting anyways.<br />
<br />
The stubborn ego inside of me wanted to continue arguing its point. It wasn&rsquo;t comfortable
giving up on a seemingly winnable argument, but it couldn&rsquo;t articulate anything stronger than
what it was facing from the other side. In the end, the two of us simply came to the same conclusion.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>There is no right answer.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Moreover, everyone has their own assessment of what is <em>right</em> or <em>wrong</em>.
It&rsquo;s not always my responsibility to change someone&rsquo;s else mind to mirror mine, but it
is my responsibility to at least think about why their answer doesn&rsquo;t align with mine.
The human condition isn&rsquo;t dictated by universal laws; you can try your best to come up with
an explanation for every quandry you face, but often you will be met with an impenetrable conclusion.</p>

<hr />

<p>Sorry, <em>Ego</em>. You&rsquo;re allowed to have an opinion, but it won&rsquo;t always be right. Sometimes, it&rsquo;ll be
flat out wrong. And sometimes, there just is no right answer. We&rsquo;ll be cool with that.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>I Made This</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/i-made-this/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 23:04:02 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/i-made-this/</guid>
			<description>This morning, I made myself an avocado toast at work. I mashed up an entire avocado, sliced up the packaged hard boiled egg, toasted the bread, assembled each topping delicately, and even applied a medley of salt and pepper on top. After a challenging, five minutes of work, I sat down at the kitchen table with my creation and admired what I had put together. It was truly a masterpiece.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<figure>
    <img src="/img/imadethis/avocado.jpg"/> 
</figure>


<p>This morning, I made myself an avocado toast at work. I mashed up an entire avocado,
sliced up the packaged hard boiled egg, toasted the bread, assembled each topping delicately,
and even applied a medley of salt and pepper on top. After a challenging, five minutes
of work, I sat down at the kitchen table with my creation and admired what I had put together.
It was truly a masterpiece. And I had made it <em>myself</em>.</p>

<hr />

<p>I rarely think about all the effort that takes place for that avocado toast to appear on my
plate in the morning. I forget that before I grab the avocado off of the shelf, a farmer
has to actually plant the seeds of the avocado trees. The avocados have to be plucked, sorted,
screened for appearance, then stickered, packaged, and shipped to the supermarket. Each
of these steps requires hundreds of workers, especially at the scale that these fruits are produced at.
And, I don&rsquo;t even know how the bread is made. But I can only imagine&hellip;<br />
<br />
When I make my avocado toast in the morning, I am literally standing on the shoulders of giants.
Every one of those steps I mentioned earlier must go right for the next to take place. Hundreds
of people have to be working together in harmony for me to enjoy my assemblage of green paste and
bread.<br />
<br />
I struggle to come up with an episode in my life that is not product of a million other events accurately
filing down an assembly line. I felt a sense of success when I bit into that toast
this morning, but success is expensive, and I don&rsquo;t always realize how much of a deal I am getting. Maybe I won&rsquo;t complain about the price
of an avocado toast the next time I&rsquo;m at brunch?</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>I Gotta Go See About a Girl</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/i-gotta-go-see-about-a-girl/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 22:47:01 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/i-gotta-go-see-about-a-girl/</guid>
			<description>Will Hunting has been gifted a prodigious brain. His mind is unlike anyone else&amp;rsquo;s before him. Yet instead of exercising his mental faculties to solve the next great mathematical challenges, he sets off for California in pursuit of the girl of his dreams.
Will Hunting is a foolish man, right? Why would he throw away an opportunity of a lifetime, all for one girl?
Well, what is more important for the soul - doing what one should do, or what one wants to do?</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Will Hunting has been gifted a prodigious brain. His mind is unlike anyone else&rsquo;s before him.
Yet instead of exercising his mental faculties to solve the next great mathematical challenges,
he sets off for California in pursuit of the girl of his dreams.<br />
<br />
Will Hunting is a foolish man, right? Why would he throw away an opportunity of a lifetime,
all for one girl?<br />
<br />
Well, what is more important for the soul - doing what one <em>should</em> do, or what one <em>wants</em> to do?
It&rsquo;s a question that has certainly weighed on everyone&rsquo;s mind at some point in time. Do I fill out
one more job application, or just flip on the tv instead? Do I go out for a run right when my alarm
kicks me out of bed at 7 am, or do I hit the snooze button and fall right into my sheets?
Each moment of the day is filled with these sorts of micro decisions. Am I doing the right thing right now?
Do I want to be doing this?<br />
<br />
How do you come up with the answers to these questions?</p>

<hr />

<p>Simple. Do what you want to do. All the time. If you don&rsquo;t want to be doing what you think
you should be doing, maybe you&rsquo;re just not cut out for doing that thing. Maybe you need
to reconsider what you believe is important to you. Don&rsquo;t spend what little time you have
doing things that only <em>seem</em> essential. If you constantly
do what you truly want to do, you might just end each day a little more satisfied with yourself. And with
what short lives we live anyhow, isn&rsquo;t that what really matters?</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>If a Tree Falls</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/if-a-tree-falls/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 23:18:53 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/if-a-tree-falls/</guid>
			<description>Every time I went out with friends, I would take a picture for my story. I needed to scroll through my feed, checking what everyone else was up to, how many people had seen my story.
 If a tree falls in a forest and no one is around to hear it, does it make a sound?
 As philosopher George Berkeley said in his work A Treatise Concerning the Principles of Human Knowledge, &amp;ldquo;The objects of sense exist only when they are perceived.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every time I went out with friends, I would take a picture for my story. I needed to scroll through
my feed, checking what everyone else was up to, how many people had seen my story.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>If a tree falls in a forest and no one is around to hear it, does it make a sound?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>As philosopher George Berkeley said in his work <em>A Treatise Concerning the Principles of Human Knowledge</em>,
&ldquo;The objects of sense exist only when they are perceived.&rdquo; I had come to believe that I wasn&rsquo;t having
enjoying myself unless someone else saw that I was doing so. If I don&rsquo;t take a photo for the gram, am
I really <em>having fun</em>?</p>

<hr />

<p>Hell yeah I am. I like to think I&rsquo;m having more fun with my life right now than anyone else I know.
I don&rsquo;t need views on an ephermal story to tell me so. Out with Instagram and Snapchat, the endless
onslaught of contrived smiles and sounds. Only I need to be privy to my own feelings of content.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Laugh</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/laugh/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 20:27:28 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/laugh/</guid>
			<description>One of most beautiful things in the entire world is laughter. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you are black or white, male or female identifying, young or old. If you are faced with a moment in life that you find amusing, you let out a giggle, or a rowdy guffaw. Of course, the quirks of life that we find humorous differ person to person. Our perception of what is &amp;ldquo;funny&amp;rdquo; is shaped by a myriad of past experiences - of trauma, joy, excitement, fear.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<figure>
    <img src="/img/laughter/howimetyourmother.jpg"/> 
</figure>


<p>One of most beautiful things in the entire world is laughter. It doesn&rsquo;t matter
if you are black or white, male or female identifying, young or old. If you are faced with
a moment in life that you find amusing, you let out a giggle, or a rowdy guffaw. Of course, the quirks of life that we find humorous differ person to person. Our perception of
what is &ldquo;funny&rdquo; is shaped by a myriad of past experiences - of trauma, joy, excitement, fear.
The often childish or esoteric jokes I crack around the coffee table don&rsquo;t always stick with my friends,
and the humor they engage in often goes over my head.<br />
<br />
Yet, wherever you come from, you too possess a deeply <em>human</em> ability to explore social boundaries through laughter.
Just like every other person, your chest and throat work in concert to belt out a wide-toothed, smile-so-hard-your-cheeks-hurt, hearty laugh,
the moment a thought tickles your mind. Laughter is a human universal. We all do it, and we should try a little harder to make
others do it as well. Sharing a laugh with someone lowers the emotional walls that stand in between the two of you,
and allows you to, over time, cultivate a real friendship in their place.<br />
<br />
Relationships are built upon the act of sharing one&rsquo;s own belongings with others - time, empathy, love.
I recently caught up with a friend late into the night, sharing vulnerable stories in their full embarassment and discomfort. Several hours later,
after thoroughly probing the depths of each other&rsquo;s inhibitions, we stopped and looked at each other.<br />
<br />
We had laid everything on the table. We had nothing left to say.<br />
So, we just laughed.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Laugh, and the whole world laughs with you.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>You Don&#39;t Have Time</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/you-dont-have-time/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 01:52:19 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/you-dont-have-time/</guid>
			<description>Today&amp;rsquo;s writing is a rather short one - sort of emblematic of the topic of the piece.
It&amp;rsquo;s 1:55 am. I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to write this piece all day, but I&amp;rsquo;ve only just gotten home and found some time for myself. I also need to get to sleep.
Telling yourself that you have more time is one of the biggest lies you will ever tell yourself. More often than not, you don&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today&rsquo;s writing is a rather short one - sort of emblematic of the topic of the piece.<br />
It&rsquo;s 1:55 am. I&rsquo;ve been meaning to write this piece all day, but I&rsquo;ve only just gotten
home and found some time for myself. I also need to get to sleep.<br />
<br />
Telling yourself that you have more time is one of the biggest lies you will ever tell yourself.
More often than not, you don&rsquo;t.
You put off signing up for next quarter&rsquo;s classes till the evening, pretend like you didn&rsquo;t
see your friend&rsquo;s text so you can instead focus on your tv show.
Soon enough, that time you had allocated to tend to your backlog is interrupted by
some other responsibility. Or, worse, that time you had accounted for and depended on stood you up. It had
better plans, and you were foolish to think it would cater to you.<br />
<br />
You are convinced that you will tackle your responsibilites at a later time, but that time
is just a myth. There are only 86400 seconds in a day - solve your problems <em>now</em>.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Writing Changed My Life</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/writing-changed-my-life/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 20:11:50 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/writing-changed-my-life/</guid>
			<description>Today marks day one of my month-long quest to paint my thoughts into words. Publicly. Truth is, I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing to myself all year. I created a bullet journal for myself at the start of 2019. I had never kept a journal before, never wrote down my thoughts, never sat down to question the ebbing of emotions and ideas that coursed through my mind. For most of my life, I had treated my subconscious as a tomb which could not be disturbed.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today marks day one of my <a href="/posts/thirty-footsteps/">month-long quest</a> to paint my thoughts into words. <em>Publicly</em>.
Truth is, I&rsquo;ve been writing to myself all year. I created a <a href="https://bulletjournal.com/">bullet journal</a>
for myself at the start of 2019. I had never kept a journal before, never wrote down my thoughts, never sat down
to question the ebbing of emotions and ideas that coursed through my mind. For most of my life, I had treated my
subconscious as a tomb which could not be disturbed. Reflecting on my emotions was difficult. I was both incapable and
unwilling to keep trying.</p>

<p>For those who don&rsquo;t know what Bullet Journaling is - it&rsquo;s a method of journaling that lets you keep track of the past,
present, and future in a style that best suits you. It&rsquo;s highly customizable, and is the perfect brain-dump, task tracker,
and reflective medium. To a person like me who had never journaled before, it was like picking up a guitar for the
first time. You give it a few strums to no avail, but you&rsquo;re immediately hooked and captivated by the thought of
producing beautiful rhythms. So, you keep strumming and keep strumming, slowly sounding more melodic each day. That&rsquo;s what
happened to me. I was getting better, and I loved it.</p>

<p>The building block of a Bullet Journal is the <em>spread</em>, a set of two open-face pages. Some examples of spreads are
daily logs, monthly logs, habit trackers, to-do list, <a href="https://www.bulletjournaladdict.com/spreads/14-bullet-journal-ideas/">etc</a>.
My favorite spread to date is my <em>Monthly Log.</em> Everyday, I jot down one significant thing that occured during the day. It gives me
a chance to reconcile the often hectic parts of the day into one memory that stands out, worthy of being remembered.
<figure>
    <img src="/img/writing/bujo.jpg"/> 
</figure>

Looking back at previous month&rsquo;s logs, I can retell a story in my mind.
I piece together each day&rsquo;s happenings into one big, beautiful narrative.
It&rsquo;s like pulling out the guitar one night and recalling that song you once struggled to learn for weeks. The chords wake
from their slumber to flow through your mind and become palpable again, vibrating through your fingers and into thin air.</p>

<p>Bullet journaling has taught me to find something great out of every day. It&rsquo;s allowed me to reinvest in writing,
a skill I had left dormant for too long. I think a bit harder now, and reflect more often than I ever had. I believe BuJo&rsquo;ing has changed my life.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Thirty One Footsteps</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/thirty-footsteps/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 21:28:32 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/thirty-footsteps/</guid>
			<description>Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about the concept of inputs and outputs. Though, this shouldn&amp;rsquo;t come as a surprise, right? I&amp;rsquo;m a computer scientist. My craft is solely concerned with transforming input to our information systems into consumable output for the outside world.
But by the end of my junior year at UCLA, I/O had become more than just the subject of that grueling chapter 23 in my computer architecture textbook.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately, I&rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about the concept of <em>inputs</em> and <em>outputs</em>. Though, this shouldn&rsquo;t come as a surprise, right? I&rsquo;m a computer scientist.
My craft is solely concerned with transforming input to our information systems into consumable output for the outside world.</p>

<p>But by the end of my junior year at UCLA, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Input/output">I/O</a> had become more than just the subject of that grueling chapter 23 in my computer architecture textbook.
The ability to correctly handle inputs and outputs determines the success of my own being just as much as any other information system.
I am just a singular computer chip plugged into a million lines of input.
Just take a second to think about this - the amount of data you and I consume on a daily basis is unfathomable. We
are perpetually plugged into our phones, television, and conversation with others.
It becomes easy to focus on just one line of input (like my phone) and block incoming traffic from others (like my mother&rsquo;s daily reminders to sleep before 1 am).</p>

<p>The voices and sights I experience everyday are inextricably linked to my own output - to the way I treat other
people, to the beliefs I espouse. As I came to realize this, I started to pay more and more attention
to the people that I spend my time with. And I&rsquo;ve been really lucky to have amazing friends and family sharing
their stories with me. If I want to provide the most value to the world as I truly can,
I have to surround myself with the best people along the way.</p>

<p>I often find myself overstepping my bounds in social situations, or not speaking up when I should have,
and regretting it afterwards. Parsing the input and determing the right output has never been easy, but it&rsquo;s a skill that
can be learned, just like any other. The more discomfort you expose yourself to, the more empathy you develop.
I&rsquo;m working on learning when to speak less and listen more, when to toss aside
what others are preaching and speak up for what I believe is right.</p>

<p>In order to keep refining this skill, I&rsquo;ve decided to spend thirty days focusing intently on
my inputs and outputs. I recently purchased a Medium membership(!) to allow myself to consume more, and have set an ambitious goal to write everyday for the
month of August. I borrowed this idea from my good friends <a href="https://medium.com/@dkb868">Dmitri Brereton</a> and <a href="https://medium.com/@ABiasedHypocrite">Jorge Fuentes</a>,
because I strongly believe in their idea of &ldquo;writing for an audience of one.&rdquo;
I don&rsquo;t mind who reads these articles, or if people find them dull, offensive, or
just downright useless. I&rsquo;m writing them for <em>me</em>, so that I truly focus on <em>my</em> inputs and outputs, one
day at a time. These are my thirty one footsteps.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>What Is DevX</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/new-what-is-devx/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 17:27:04 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/new-what-is-devx/</guid>
			<description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently serving as President of UCLA DevX this upcoming school year. We’ve recently felt the need to answer a few questions about ourselves and our mission, both to hold ourselves accountable and to inform the general public. These are questions that have not been answered since the club’s founding four quarters ago, but will hopefully clarify our intent for all parties involved. These are our guiding principles, values, and goals for the future.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>I&rsquo;m currently serving as President of UCLA DevX this upcoming school year.
We’ve recently felt the need to answer a few questions about ourselves and our
mission, both to hold ourselves accountable and to inform the general public.
These are questions that have not been answered since the club’s founding four
quarters ago, but will hopefully clarify our intent for all parties involved.
These are our guiding principles, values, and goals for the future.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>If you have any questions you’d like answered about DevX after reading this,
please reach out to any of us on Facebook, email, in person, etc!</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="what-is-devx">What is DevX:</h2>

<p>DevX is an umbrella organization for product teams, and a
technology and entrepreneurship thought leader.</p>

<h2 id="what-is-the-devx-mission">What is the DevX Mission:</h2>

<p>To provide students real life experiences to turn
theory into application and create products that people love. We give them an
opportunity to go through the entire life-cycle of a product: from ideation to
MVP to user acquisition.</p>

<h2 id="what-separates-us-from-other-tech-clubs-on-campus">What separates us from other tech clubs on campus:</h2>

<p>As a product development
focused organization, our team structure is inspired directly from industry and
our goals have more in common with new tech startups than student organizations.
You will directly deal with many of these practical challenges and grapple with
the consequences of product choices in a real way. But beyond development, we
also seek to launch all our products and continuously evaluate them to maximise
user experience. This adds deployment and maintenance to the lifecycle, all of
which are key transferable skills to industry. We aren’t an engineering club; we
are a constantly evolving club that recruits students across the spectrum to
keep up with the requirements just like a growing startup!</p>

<h2 id="what-do-we-do-on-a-daily-basis">What do we do on a daily basis:</h2>

<p>The teams in our organization largely function
as independent units. Depending on the team you are on, you might meet as a team
once or a few times a week to go over the next tasks needed to build, analyze,
and market your product. Teams usually set a goal for the quarter, and spend
every week working towards achieving those goals, such as “Finish our MVP by the
end of the quarter,” or “Release to our beta users and understand what we need
to do next from their feedback.” We also hold a general meetings once a week as
a whole club with different activities planned throughout the quarter. One of
the meetings is for an internal demo day, where we share with other teams the progress
you have made. Another meeting is reserved for our public Demo Day, where we
invite students to come learn more about the products you are working on.</p>

<h2 id="what-kind-of-people-does-devx-recruit">What kind of people does DevX recruit:</h2>

<p>DevX recruits talented and passionate students who care about working as a team,
learning new skills, and building things that matter. In the past, DevX broadly
recruited for three positions: Designer, Developer, and Product Manager. The
Designer was responsible for creating the UI and UX of the product. The
Developer was responsible for implementing the designs, and building out the
backend services of the product. The Product Manager was responsible for
creating the product roadmap, and keeping their team on schedule.  We’ve
recently felt limited by these strict roles, and are moving towards a more fluid
recruiting system. We’ve identified roles that we think every team should have,
but encourage people to brainstorm creative ways they can use their skills to
help the team, and apply if interested!</p>

<h2 id="what-do-we-do-besides-work-in-teams">What do we do besides work in teams:</h2>

<p>Tech Talks, Speaker Series, Boba runs,
internal hackathons (new), our famous Moonshots––we do a ton! One of our values
is building a community and family within our club, and we are committed to
finding ways to network and grow together.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>24 Hours in San Francisco</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/24-hours-in-sf/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 20:07:56 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/24-hours-in-sf/</guid>
			<description>This weekend, I had the pleasure of hosting my good friend Eric Siegel in the Bay Area. I wanted to show him around San Francisco - my favorite sights from the times I visited, the must-see tourist attractions, the classic SF experience. Eric was only in town for two nights, and I had to make sure that the little time he had here was lacking of a dull moment. So on Saturday morning at 10 am, we each packed a change of clothes, and set out to see what we could experience in 24 hours.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>This weekend, I had the pleasure of hosting my good friend <a href="https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100013556977844&amp;hc_ref=ARTCibTsupEQodn4C6prs6WeRj8GaLwOEr693rnYlgNoNpAQu1fu80DNn25LQKkt8rk&amp;__tn__=lC-R">Eric Siegel</a> in the Bay Area. I wanted to show him around San Francisco - my favorite sights from the times I visited, the must-see tourist attractions, the classic SF experience. Eric was only in town for two nights, and I had to make sure that the little time he had here was lacking of a dull moment. So on Saturday morning at 10 am, we each packed a change of clothes, and set out to see what we could experience in 24 hours. Here&rsquo;s all that we accomplished.</p>

<h2 id="the-dropoff">The Dropoff</h2>

<p>After doing some hasty research prior to our departure, I had come to the conclusion that the <a href="https://www.sfmta.com/garages-lots/north-beach-garage">North Beach Parking Garage</a> would be the safest place to park a car overnight. For a full 24 hours, we would have to pay only $36. At exactly 12 pm on Saturday, we arrive at the parking garage, collect our belongings, and say farewell to the car.</p>

<h2 id="the-cable-cars">The Cable Cars</h2>

<p>Our first destination is the Powell/Mason Cable Car turnaround, to ride the leisurely SF cable cars. We board the car just a few minutes before it is ready to depart. Eric pulls his camera out of his bag.
<img class="snap-image" src="/img/24-hours/cable.jpeg" /><br />
And we&rsquo;re ready to go! Along the way, we see some sweet views of the Bay Bridge creeping in between tall buildings. We wave at European tourists, who generally wave back.</p>

<h2 id="the-gardens">The Gardens</h2>

<p>The cable car lets off at Union Square, and we&rsquo;re thrown into a swarm of shoppers lugging around large bags filled to the brim from stores who&rsquo;s names I can not pronounce. At this point, it&rsquo;s around 1 PM, and we&rsquo;re both very hungry. We throw some searches into Yelp, and come across a salad place called Mixt (think Chipotle for even healthier people). We pick up some food to go, walk across the street to the Yerba Buena gardens, and sit down on the grass with our meals.
<img class="snap-image" src="/img/24-hours/lunch.jpeg" /><br />
There is an Asian music festival taking place in the Gardens at the same time, so we chew on our dressed leaves and veggies while listening to an orchestra of child musicians.</p>

<h2 id="the-lew">The Lew</h2>

<p>After lunch, we head to the <a href="https://www.thecjm.org/">Contemporay Jewish Museum</a>. Eric is Jewish, and I love museums. Naturally, we had to visit.<br />
The main attraction is a new exhibit titled <a href="https://www.thecjm.org/exhibitions/103">Lew the Jew and his Circle</a>. It details the life of a Jewish-American tattoo artist living in NYC in the early 1900s. Albert Morton Kurzman, or &ldquo;Lew the Jew,&rdquo; fought in the Spanish-American War, and learned the art of tattooing in the Phillipines. He brought the art back to states, so that kids like Eric and I could now stand and wonder how pissed our parents would be if we came back home with tattoos.</p>

<h2 id="the-climb">The Climb</h2>

<p>After exiting the museum feeling more rebellious than usual, we decide to take up the suggestion of our good friend <a href="https://www.facebook.com/bryson.levisay?fb_dtsg_ag=Adwws3Kyd9Y28sMB1vO9BKq3QYKuFTupJP4Z3Q0d_5kmCg%3AAdy-ClFfN2BHsq7NW6fkF1_JX52YjXce2CX_6cSaE1hDRA">Bryson Levisay</a> and walk from the Embarcadero, up the Filbert Steps, to Coit Tower. I silently beg my sweat glands to stay closed as we climb up the 31.5% grade vertical.<br />
Upon reaching the top of the staircase, we wait in line to pay for our ticket, and then wait in line again to take the elevator to the top. The view is pristine. The wild breeze wipes the beads of sweat right off of my skin.
<img src="/img/24-hours/coit.JPG" /></p>

<h2 id="the-meal">The Meal</h2>

<p>It is now approaching 6 pm, and we are yet again craving another meal. This time, in the heart of Little Italy, we sit down in a small Asian restaurant. A lady walks in demanding to use the restroom. The server, who speaks little English, asks that she leave. The lady cusses out everyone everyone in the restaurant and angrily storms out. Our friend <a href="https://www.facebook.com/paul.ramstad.5?fb_dtsg_ag=Adwws3Kyd9Y28sMB1vO9BKq3QYKuFTupJP4Z3Q0d_5kmCg%3AAdy-ClFfN2BHsq7NW6fkF1_JX52YjXce2CX_6cSaE1hDRA">Paul Ramstad</a>, who has graciously offered to house us for the night, walks in to meet us. We quickly pay the tab and leave.</p>

<h2 id="the-show">The Show</h2>

<p>Earlier in the day, I bought tickets to see <a href="http://stevetrevino.com/">Steve Trefino</a> perform at <a href="http://www.cobbscomedy.com/">Cobb&rsquo;s Comedy Club</a>. We head to the club and are seated near the back of a packed but intimate feeling room. At 7:30 pm sharp, the MC comes out to get us warmed up. He is gay and Latino, and isn&rsquo;t afraid to piss off some heads in the room with his hilarious insights into his vision of minotiry communities.<br />
The headliner, Steve, sufficiently leaves us in tears by the end of the night. At one point, I am keeled over at the hip, ferociously belting out laughter, hoping that he takes a pause for me to catch my breath. It was devastatingly hilarious.</p>

<h2 id="the-scoop">The Scoop</h2>

<p>After the show ends, Eric, Paul, and I take to North Beach in search of something to satisfy our sweet tooth.
We stumble into a gelato store, order ourselves a few scoops, and share our favorite lines from the show back and forth.</p>

<h2 id="the-mission">The Mission</h2>

<p>We deem the journey back to Paul&rsquo;s apartment in the Mission District too far to walk, and call an Uber to take us back.
Paul preps us with the facts on his tiny living space during the ride over.<br><br>
Once we arrive, we are pleasantly surprised. The place is just as small, if not smaller, as Paul had described. One bathroom, two bedrooms,
and a room with a fridge and square countertop that was to be known as &lsquo;the kitchen.&rsquo; The monthly rates are outrageous. We witness the process of
gentrification first hand, but collectively agree that there is nothing we can do. It is just the way it is now.<br><br>
We play one of Steve&rsquo;s older shows on Netflix. We hear many of the same jokes&ndash;we are glad that we heard them first live. Too tired to venture back out
into the city, we set up for the night and go to sleep.</p>

<h2 id="the-morning">The Morning</h2>

<p>We search for a cozy brunch spot in the mission. It is crazy how one moment, we are walking
in the midst of a historically significant neighborhood with largely much of its history
intact, but in the next we see skyscrapers and urbanization abound. The city has that jaggedness
to it. Brunch was excellent as well.</p>

<h2 id="the-departure">The Departure</h2>

<p>23 hours and 58 minutes later, we are back at the car, punching in our ticket to avoid
a large fine. We look back at the past 24 hours, at all the events that made up each memory.
Incredible.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>The Beginning</title>
			<link>https://ramgo.li/posts/the-beginning/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 20:10:33 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/the-beginning/</guid>
			<description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to create this blog for a long time now. The biggest two reasons that have been eating at my brain for a while now are as follows
 Life has gotten super hectic lately, and I feel that if I don&amp;rsquo;t slow down to recollect my thoughts/memories every once in a while, they will vanish. I&amp;rsquo;m a big believer in memories, and experiences. I really value the past, and my goal is that, here, I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to hold onto some of it.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been meaning to create this blog for a long time now. The biggest two reasons that have been
eating at my brain for a while now are as follows</p>

<ul>
<li>Life has gotten super hectic lately, and I feel that if I don&rsquo;t slow down to recollect
my thoughts/memories every once in a while, they will vanish. I&rsquo;m a big believer in memories,
and experiences. I really value the past, and my goal is that, here, I&rsquo;ll be able to hold
onto some of it.</li>
<li>I feel that I still haven&rsquo;t found my real voice. I sometimes find that I
act different around my different groups of friends, and I can&rsquo;t quite figure out why. Maybe it&rsquo;s beacuse
I care too much about what people think of me, and I have this idea that <em>other</em> people have an ideal
version of me, and I need to live up to that ideal. But I&rsquo;m not too big of a fan of that. Maybe here,
I&rsquo;ll start to whittle away at the one voice that I really like, my voice.</li>
</ul>

<p>I used to read <em>a lot</em> of tech blog articles. And I still do. But lately, I&rsquo;ve been straying away from
that weathered trail. It&rsquo;s been awesome. I&rsquo;ve been debating with my friends about
really intriguing/mind-bending topics. I&rsquo;ve been trying to open up to my friends more. I go on Medium
and read stories written by mothers who deal with the stress of post-labor. There&rsquo;s a lot of life out there.
So much to experience!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m going to try and write frequently. Maybe once a week? Ideally everyday, but I&rsquo;m not really an idealist.
I&rsquo;m just going to try my best.</p>

<p>Cheers</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
