<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ram Goli</title>
    <link>https://ramgo.li/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ram Goli</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 22:20:40 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ramgo.li/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled Thoughts: On Giving Up</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/on-giving-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 22:20:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/on-giving-up/</guid>
      <description>So many articles out there preach &amp;ldquo;proven methods to never give up.&amp;rdquo; We live in such a fast-paced society where execution and forward progress is worshipped. Quitting on a challenge, task, or idea can make us feel weak, and is often frowned upon. It feels like we aren&amp;rsquo;t strong enough to finish what we set out to accomplish, or like we don&amp;rsquo;t have the mental resolve to persevere. Giving up practicing the trumpet after starting college always nagged at the back of my mind like a lonely child who tugs at the bottom of his father&amp;rsquo;s coat, innocently pleading for more attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning To Ask</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/just-ask/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 22:21:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/just-ask/</guid>
      <description>Solving your own problems is next to impossible when you have no idea where to begin. This glaring issue strikes me so often at work, and even more so in my personal life. I am faced with some challenging hurdle to jump over, but I have no context to draw help from.
I think the biggest blocker in these situations is my hesitancy to turn to someone else for help. There was a time when I was taking CS131 and was stuck on the third or fourth homework assignment for what felt like days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living Content</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/living-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 21:17:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/living-content/</guid>
      <description>I just came back from a camping trip with friends with several fresh thoughts ready to brew.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved being entrenched in the wilderness, ever since I went on my first mountain biking trip through the careening hill of Mt. Tam during the sixth grade. I even wrote my UC college essay on that experience, and it somehow landed me a spot in UCLA. Crazy.
Anyways, being lost in the trees has always been the state of being that I gravitate to most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being a Better Child</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/being-a-better-child/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 23:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/being-a-better-child/</guid>
      <description>I suspect that I haven&amp;rsquo;t been a very good child as of late. I often forget to text my mother back. I don&amp;rsquo;t spend as much time with my parents when I&amp;rsquo;m back home as I should. I find myself subconsciously avoiding conversation with them, rather than investing in it. These facts have led me to come up with a list of demands for myself/habits to form. Here goes.
 I will text my mother once every day I will call my parents (at least) every other day Before going back to school, I will spend (at least) one entire day solely in their company I will verbally tell them how important they are to me and my success  It&amp;rsquo;s time to stop feeling guilty for being a distant son.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal Debates</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/internal-debates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 23:43:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/internal-debates/</guid>
      <description>I spend way too much time in my own head.
I am often the moderator of a debate between two bitter enemies clashing head to head, which takes place after nearly every social interaction I have with people. Voice #1 in my head will say &amp;ldquo;Ram, you should&amp;rsquo;ve said this just a minute ago,&amp;rdquo; while Voice #2 will immediately interject with a &amp;ldquo;No Ram, you should&amp;rsquo;ve said that instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivation</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 23:32:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/motivation/</guid>
      <description>Finding motivation to accomplish something can be a difficult challenge, especially when you need to also motivate those around you. Talking about how difficult the job can be if not everyone is doing their part can dampen spirits, and relying on enthusiasm and excitement in your speech is not always sustainable.
I think the best way to bring out motivation in others is create alignment. If you start with a high level mission, a &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re going to Mars&amp;rdquo; type moonshot, its easy to break it down into several sub-objectives in support of that high level mission, and continue to break them down into actionable accomplishments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled Thoughts: Free Will</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/free-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 22:06:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/free-will/</guid>
      <description>Free will doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist. The idea that humans have control over their thoughts, and thus over their actions, can not be true. We are an amalgamation of chemical and biological processes, which obey the laws of physics, rather than our own will. Given any set of inputs, our brains will always act in the same manner, every time. It&amp;rsquo;s like plugging in values into some convoluted quadratic formula. If you give the equation the same inputs, it will always output the same value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confirmation Bias</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/confirmation-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 15:47:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/confirmation-bias/</guid>
      <description>We largely tune into the same news channels, follow the same twitter feeds, subscribe to the same youtube channels that feed into our already fine-tuned perception of the outside world, of the &amp;ldquo;other side.&amp;rdquo; We hang out with those who espouse the same beliefs we do, and are quick to dismiss the opinions coming from the opposite end of the spectrum.
No individual is at fault for demonstrating such commonplace behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Universal Adapter</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/the-universal-adapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 23:47:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/the-universal-adapter/</guid>
      <description>The Universal Adapter, in my own words, possesses the unique trait of hyper-compatibility. Anyone can approach the Univeral Adapter, plug into them, and instantly be exposed to a source of warmth and friendship. A Universal Adapter is an idealized social construct - a human being capable of befriending anyone.
Does the Universal Adapter exist?
And if so, how is it possible? How can someone truly be friends with anyone?
I&amp;rsquo;ve recently stumbled across the key to universal compatibility, thanks to the prior work of my new friend AB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Dissonance</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/cognitive-dissonance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 23:12:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/cognitive-dissonance/</guid>
      <description>The feeling of discomfort when your beliefs run counter to your behaviors.
 It&amp;rsquo;s that itch that you can&amp;rsquo;t seem to scratch deep within the back of your mind. What do you do to get rid of it? You only have two options right? You either change your beliefs, or you change your behaviors.
But what if you can&amp;rsquo;t just change either? You&amp;rsquo;ve become too comfortable with your behavior to justify doing anything else, and you&amp;rsquo;re too stubborn to let go of your beliefs so easily.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>