<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog | Ram Goli</title>
    <link>https://blog.ramsgoli.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blog | Ram Goli</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 17:27:04 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.ramsgoli.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is DevX</title>
      <link>https://blog.ramsgoli.com/posts/new-what-is-devx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 17:27:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ramsgoli.com/posts/new-what-is-devx/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently serving as President of UCLA DevX this upcoming school year. We’ve recently felt the need to answer a few questions about ourselves and our mission, both to hold ourselves accountable and to inform the general public. These are questions that have not been answered since the club’s founding four quarters ago, but will hopefully clarify our intent for all parties involved. These are our guiding principles, values, and goals for the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24 Hours in San Francisco</title>
      <link>https://blog.ramsgoli.com/posts/24-hours-in-sf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 20:07:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ramsgoli.com/posts/24-hours-in-sf/</guid>
      <description>This weekend, I had the pleasure of hosting my good friend Eric Siegel in the Bay Area. I wanted to show him around San Francisco - my favorite sights from the times I visited, the must-see tourist attractions, the classic SF experience. Eric was only in town for two nights, and I had to make sure that the little time he had here was lacking of a dull moment. So on Saturday morning at 10 am, we each packed a change of clothes, and set out to see what we could experience in 24 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginning</title>
      <link>https://blog.ramsgoli.com/posts/the-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 20:10:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ramsgoli.com/posts/the-beginning/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to create this blog for a long time now. The biggest two reasons that have been eating at my brain for a while now are as follows
 Life has gotten super hectic lately, and I feel that if I don&amp;rsquo;t slow down to recollect my thoughts/memories every once in a while, they will vanish. I&amp;rsquo;m a big believer in memories, and experiences. I really value the past, and my goal is that, here, I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to hold onto some of it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>