<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ram Goli</title>
    <link>https://ramgo.li/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ram Goli</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 15:47:27 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ramgo.li/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Confirmation Bias</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/confirmation-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 15:47:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/confirmation-bias/</guid>
      <description>We largely tune into the same news channels, follow the same twitter feeds, subscribe to the same youtube channels that feed into our already fine-tuned perception of the outside world, of the &amp;ldquo;other side.&amp;rdquo; We hang out with those who espouse the same beliefs we do, and are quick to dismiss the opinions coming from the opposite end of the spectrum.
No individual is at fault for demonstrating such commonplace behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Universal Adapter</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/the-universal-adapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 23:47:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/the-universal-adapter/</guid>
      <description>The Universal Adapter, in my own words, possesses the unique trait of hyper-compatibility. Anyone can approach the Univeral Adapter, plug into them, and instantly be exposed to a source of warmth and friendship. A Universal Adapter is an idealized social construct - a human being capable of befriending anyone.
Does the Universal Adapter exist?
And if so, how is it possible? How can someone truly be friends with anyone?
I&amp;rsquo;ve recently stumbled across the key to universal compatibility, thanks to the prior work of my new friend AB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Dissonance</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/cognitive-dissonance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 23:12:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/cognitive-dissonance/</guid>
      <description>The feeling of discomfort when your beliefs run counter to your behaviors.
 It&amp;rsquo;s that itch that you can&amp;rsquo;t seem to scratch deep within the back of your mind. What do you do to get rid of it? You only have two options right? You either change your beliefs, or you change your behaviors.
But what if you can&amp;rsquo;t just change either? You&amp;rsquo;ve become too comfortable with your behavior to justify doing anything else, and you&amp;rsquo;re too stubborn to let go of your beliefs so easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There Is No Right Answer</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/there-is-no-right-answer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 22:55:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/there-is-no-right-answer/</guid>
      <description>The questions that bother me the most are the ones that I can never come up with an answer to. They leave behind a queasy aftertaste that I just can&amp;rsquo;t get rid of. I love being proven wrong in an argument, because the defeat will add something new to my reportoire of reasoning. But when we reach a stalemate, it feels queasy, and unsatisfactory. We made it so far, right to the edge of the cliff overlooking the eager blue waters below, but we won&amp;rsquo;t make the jump.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Made This</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/i-made-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 23:04:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/i-made-this/</guid>
      <description>This morning, I made myself an avocado toast at work. I mashed up an entire avocado, sliced up the packaged hard boiled egg, toasted the bread, assembled each topping delicately, and even applied a medley of salt and pepper on top. After a challenging, five minutes of work, I sat down at the kitchen table with my creation and admired what I had put together. It was truly a masterpiece.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Gotta Go See About a Girl</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/i-gotta-go-see-about-a-girl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 22:47:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/i-gotta-go-see-about-a-girl/</guid>
      <description>Will Hunting has been gifted a prodigious brain. His mind is unlike anyone else&amp;rsquo;s before him. Yet instead of exercising his mental faculties to solve the next great mathematical challenges, he sets off for California in pursuit of the girl of his dreams.
Will Hunting is a foolish man, right? Why would he throw away an opportunity of a lifetime, all for one girl?
Well, what is more important for the soul - doing what one should do, or what one wants to do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If a Tree Falls</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/if-a-tree-falls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 23:18:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/if-a-tree-falls/</guid>
      <description>Every time I went out with friends, I would take a picture for my story. I needed to scroll through my feed, checking what everyone else was up to, how many people had seen my story.
 If a tree falls in a forest and no one is around to hear it, does it make a sound?
 As philosopher George Berkeley said in his work A Treatise Concerning the Principles of Human Knowledge, &amp;ldquo;The objects of sense exist only when they are perceived.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laugh</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/laugh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 20:27:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/laugh/</guid>
      <description>One of most beautiful things in the entire world is laughter. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you are black or white, male or female identifying, young or old. If you are faced with a moment in life that you find amusing, you let out a giggle, or a rowdy guffaw. Of course, the quirks of life that we find humorous differ person to person. Our perception of what is &amp;ldquo;funny&amp;rdquo; is shaped by a myriad of past experiences - of trauma, joy, excitement, fear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Don&#39;t Have Time</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/you-dont-have-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 01:52:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/you-dont-have-time/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s writing is a rather short one - sort of emblematic of the topic of the piece.
It&amp;rsquo;s 1:55 am. I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to write this piece all day, but I&amp;rsquo;ve only just gotten home and found some time for myself. I also need to get to sleep.
Telling yourself that you have more time is one of the biggest lies you will ever tell yourself. More often than not, you don&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Changed My Life</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/writing-changed-my-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 20:11:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/writing-changed-my-life/</guid>
      <description>Today marks day one of my month-long quest to paint my thoughts into words. Publicly. Truth is, I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing to myself all year. I created a bullet journal for myself at the start of 2019. I had never kept a journal before, never wrote down my thoughts, never sat down to question the ebbing of emotions and ideas that coursed through my mind. For most of my life, I had treated my subconscious as a tomb which could not be disturbed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>