<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>untagged on Ram Goli</title>
    <link>https://ramgo.li/tags/untagged/</link>
    <description>Recent content in untagged on Ram Goli</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 21:17:15 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ramgo.li/tags/untagged/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Living Content</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/living-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 21:17:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/living-content/</guid>
      <description>I just came back from a camping trip with friends with several fresh thoughts ready to brew.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved being entrenched in the wilderness, ever since I went on my first mountain biking trip through the careening hill of Mt. Tam during the sixth grade. I even wrote my UC college essay on that experience, and it somehow landed me a spot in UCLA. Crazy.
Anyways, being lost in the trees has always been the state of being that I gravitate to most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being a Better Child</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/being-a-better-child/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 23:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/being-a-better-child/</guid>
      <description>I suspect that I haven&amp;rsquo;t been a very good child as of late. I often forget to text my mother back. I don&amp;rsquo;t spend as much time with my parents when I&amp;rsquo;m back home as I should. I find myself subconsciously avoiding conversation with them, rather than investing in it. These facts have led me to come up with a list of demands for myself/habits to form. Here goes.
 I will text my mother once every day I will call my parents (at least) every other day Before going back to school, I will spend (at least) one entire day solely in their company I will verbally tell them how important they are to me and my success  It&amp;rsquo;s time to stop feeling guilty for being a distant son.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal Debates</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/internal-debates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 23:43:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/internal-debates/</guid>
      <description>I spend way too much time in my own head.
I am often the moderator of a debate between two bitter enemies clashing head to head, which takes place after nearly every social interaction I have with people. Voice #1 in my head will say &amp;ldquo;Ram, you should&amp;rsquo;ve said this just a minute ago,&amp;rdquo; while Voice #2 will immediately interject with a &amp;ldquo;No Ram, you should&amp;rsquo;ve said that instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Universal Adapter</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/the-universal-adapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 23:47:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/the-universal-adapter/</guid>
      <description>The Universal Adapter, in my own words, possesses the unique trait of hyper-compatibility. Anyone can approach the Univeral Adapter, plug into them, and instantly be exposed to a source of warmth and friendship. A Universal Adapter is an idealized social construct - a human being capable of befriending anyone.
Does the Universal Adapter exist?
And if so, how is it possible? How can someone truly be friends with anyone?
I&amp;rsquo;ve recently stumbled across the key to universal compatibility, thanks to the prior work of my new friend AB.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>