<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>untagged on Ram Goli</title>
    <link>https://ramgo.li/tags/untagged/</link>
    <description>Recent content in untagged on Ram Goli</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 15:47:27 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ramgo.li/tags/untagged/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Confirmation Bias</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/confirmation-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 15:47:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/confirmation-bias/</guid>
      <description>We largely tune into the same news channels, follow the same twitter feeds, subscribe to the same youtube channels that feed into our already fine-tuned perception of the outside world, of the &amp;ldquo;other side.&amp;rdquo; We hang out with those who espouse the same beliefs we do, and are quick to dismiss the opinions coming from the opposite end of the spectrum.
No individual is at fault for demonstrating such commonplace behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Universal Adapter</title>
      <link>https://ramgo.li/posts/the-universal-adapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 23:47:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramgo.li/posts/the-universal-adapter/</guid>
      <description>The Universal Adapter, in my own words, possesses the unique trait of hyper-compatibility. Anyone can approach the Univeral Adapter, plug into them, and instantly be exposed to a source of warmth and friendship. A Universal Adapter is an idealized social construct - a human being capable of befriending anyone.
Does the Universal Adapter exist?
And if so, how is it possible? How can someone truly be friends with anyone?
I&amp;rsquo;ve recently stumbled across the key to universal compatibility, thanks to the prior work of my new friend AB.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>